retrotogo.com 2018-06-21

# Cookie use and privacy policy - David Walker

**Cookie Policy**

Like the majority of websites in the world, this one uses cookies – small text files stored on your computer by your browser, which help us to develop the site by checking traffic on the websites we run, support affiliate programs or post ads that are relevant to site users. They do not include personal information (like your name, for example) and do not damage files.

We may use this information (and share it with third party business partners) to observe your internet use and to compile data in order to improve the site, target advertising to you and assess general effectiveness of such advertising.

If the settings on your browser or software you use to view this website are adjusted to accept cookies we take this, and your continued use of the site, to mean that you are fine with cookie use. If you do not agree with cookies being used, the information below will explain how to stop using cookies and how to opt out of the ones used on our sites.

Note that we take no responsibility with regard to any changes you make to your own computer. It is your own choice if you turn off cookies in your web browser – and your browsing experience across various websites may be diminished.

Any changes to this policy will be posted here. We reserve the right to vary this Cookie Policy from time to time, with changes effective as soon as they are posted.

**Important footnote:  
**Please note that you can learn about online advertising and cookies at [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/), with the option to opt out of almost all advertising cookies at the [same site](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices). Opting out doesn’t necessarily mean you will not see ads, but they will not be tailored to you after you opt out.

**Our use of cookies:**

We may collect information automatically when you visit the website, using cookies. You can choose not to allow cookies. If you do, we can’t guarantee that your experience with the website will be at the standard as allowing cookies or that the site will function correctly.

As we said previously, the information collected by cookies does not personally identify you – it includes general information about your computer settings, your connection to the Internet eg operating system and platform, IP address, your browsing patterns and timings of browsing on the website and your location.

Most internet browsers accept cookies automatically, but you can change the settings of your browser to erase cookies or prevent automatic acceptance if you prefer. Turning off cookies will impact on all the sites you visit, not just this one. Links on how to turn off cookies can be found here.

[Internet Explorer](http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835) or[ Internet Explorer (mobile version)](http://%20/www.microsoft.com/windowsphone/en-us/howto/wp7/web/changing-privacy-and-other-browser-settings.aspx).  
[Apple Safari](http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Safari/5.0/en/9277.html) (or for mobile version, [look here](http://support.apple.com/kb/HT1677))  

**Cookies used on this site:**

We use the following cookies on this site, which you can opt out of via the provided links. Again, please consider carefully before you do this, as your actions will impact on all sites visited using these cookies, not just this one.

**Important:** We work with Google via Google Analytics and Google Adsense. You can [find out how Google uses data when you use this site here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/). In addition, you can [control the information sent to Google here](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/). Google also has a [Q&A about ads here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/1634057?hl=en&rd=1).

**Google Analytics:**  
We use Google Analytics on this site to monitor general traffic in order to improve the performance and content of those site. In short, we use the traffic data to do things better.

If you do not want to be included in this data, you can [opt out here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Google Adsense:**  
This site uses third party banner and ads, served via the Google Adsense program. They pay for the site you enjoy for free. Google as a third-party vendor, uses cookies (including the DART cookie) to serve ads on the site, based on previous visits to this site and other sites. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to these ads, check out the [Privacy policy](https://support.google.com/adsense/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&utm_medium=link&gsessionid=DyXLmLB1J1MxXckh6tX6AQ&utm_campaign=ww-ww-et-asfe_&utm_source=aso&answer=48182), as well as details on [how to opt-out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/).

**Skimlinks:**  
Our website contains some affiliate marketing links using the Skimlinks service, which means we get paid commission on sales of some products or services we write about. Again, they help to pay for a site you enjoy for free. Our editorial content is not influenced by advertisers or affiliate partnerships. We use a 3rd Party to enable these affiliate partnerships. You can read their [Privacy Policy here](http://skimlinks.com/privacy-policy#users) and find more information on the cookies they use and opting out, [visit this page](http://skimlinks.com/user-cookies).

**Amazon:**  
Our websites contain some affiliate links for the Amazon Associates program. If you want to know more about the use of cookies and how to opt of their use, please [visit here](http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=502584#c).

**Post Affiliate Pro:**  
One of out third-party affiliates (End Clothing) uses the Post Affiliate Pro software to monitor sales, which in turn uses cookies to track traffic from our sites to the retailer. The program is run by Quality Unit, with details of their Privacy Policy and cookies [found here](http://www.qualityunit.com/company/privacy-policy-quality-unit/).

**Affiliate Window:**  
We work with Affiliate Window for affiliate marketing for a select group of retailers. Again, you can read the Privacy Policy of this company and details of cookies[ here](http://www.affiliatewindow.com/documents/Privacy%20Policy.pdf).

**Other ad-management services:**  
We do not currently use other ad-serving programs, but when we do, we will list any details here in regards to cookies.

**Typepad:**  
Some of the Modculture sites run on the Typepad platform. A cookie is used in this instance to track visitors and visits, in order to create statistics for the platform. If you are a Typepad account holder and logged into the service, a cookie will allow you to comment on different sites, as well as continuing to access your own.

You can find out more and opt out of the Typepad cookie [here](http://help.typepad.com/typepad-and-cookies.html).

**Disqus:**  
We use the Disqus commenting system on some of our sites, with the option to log in and be remembered for future comments. This does, of course, use cookies. Details of blocking cookies for the company in your browser [can be found here](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466235-use-of-cookies).

**Third-party service cookies:**

Some third-party services are occasionally used in conjunction with our websites and could use cookies. If you want to opt out of these services, the details for doing that are found in the following places:  
[Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other) (social network)  
[Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy) (social network)  
[Pinterest](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy) (social network)  
[YouTube ](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/faq/#toc-cookies)(video player)  
[Nrelate](http://nrelate.com/privacy-policy/) (related links)  
[Vimeo](http://vimeo.com/privacy) (video player)

Any further cookie use for this site will be listed here as and when they are used.

**Privacy Policy:**

Our privacy policy relates to all of the websites in the Modculture Media group, all of which are based in the United Kingdom. This privacy policy explains what information (if any) is collected by the sites and how it is used. All of our sites, with the exception of forums, are free to access, without the need to disclose any personally identifiable information about yourself.

By using one of our sites or submitting information to us in any way, you signify your consent to our use and disclosure of information in accordance with this privacy policy. If you do not agree with this privacy policy, you must not use the site or submit information to us through or in connection with the site.

**The information collected by the site**

We access personal information including but not limited to your name, postal address, email address, telephone number, for running and maintaining any email mailouts, competition entries you have subscribed to, publishing comments, in relation to our forums and for website enquiries We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website, These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. This includes Google as a third-party vendor, which uses cookies (including the DART cookie) to serve ads on the site, based on previous visits to this site and other sites. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used, please [click here](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy.html).

We do not use any personal information except for the express purpose of carrying out the functions stated. Your personal details will not be passed to a third party without your consent unless stated in this privacy policy and all competition entries are discarded at competition end. If you wish to remove yourself from any email lists, all mailouts have an unsubscribe link. You can also permanently delete any forum accounts you may have. If you have any concerns regarding information collected by the site, contact us via the Modculture Media site.

We also gather this information and statistics for the purposes of monitoring site usage and may provide such aggregate information to third parties. These statistics will not include personal information that can be used to identify you.

If you choose to post messages in our forum or other message/comment areas (where we provide such capability), that information can be retained as necessary to resolve disputes and deal with issues relating to the law.

**Security of information**

The internet is never 100 per cent safe, but we do try our upmost to keep all information and data as secure as possible. Where you have been allocated a user admin area as part of one of our sites, this area is protected by your user name and password, which you should never divulge to anyone else.

Please be aware that communications over the internet (including email) are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered – this is the nature of the net. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control.

We believe that we have appropriate policies, rules and measures in place to protect the personal data that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification, unlawful destruction or accidental loss. Everyone in the employ of Modculture Media associated with, the processing of your personal information are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors’ information.

We also ensure that your information will not be disclosed to government institutions or authorities except if required by law or when requested to by regulatory bodies or law enforcement organisations.

**Disclosure of information**

As stated above, we do not offer specific personal information about any of our visitors to third parties unless stated in the privacy policy. Information can only be accessed by employees of Modculture Media and related contractors (including but not limited to IT support services). The only possible exceptions to this are:  
Government bodies and law enforcement agencies and in response to other legal and regulatory requests.  
Auditors or contractors or other advisers auditing, assisting with or advising on any of our business purposes.

**Your rights in relation to your information**

You can email us at any time to obtain a list of any information we currently hold about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected or to request the information is erased. We will need your full name and address and brief details of the information you require. Furthermore, we would also require proof of your identity before any details are divulged. We may charge a fee to cover the administration costs involved in providing you with a copy of your information.

**Consent and changes to this privacy policy**

By submitting any personal information to us you consent to the use of information as set out in this policy. We reserve the right to amend or modify this privacy policy and if we do so we will post the changes on this page. It is your responsibility to check the privacy policy every time you submit information to us. Use will signify that you agree to any such changes.

**Use of your personal information submitted to other sites**

We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you accessed the third party site using links from one of our sites. We recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit and contact the owner or operator of that site if you have concerns or questions.

**Further information**

For further information from us on data protection and privacy or any requests concerning your personal information please email us via the Modculture Media site.
